good day and welcome to the icici
lombard general insurance limited
q4 fy20 earnings conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today mr bhargav dasgupta
md and ceo of the company mr
pal balachandran cfo mr sanji mantri
executive director
retail and mr allah agarwal executive
director wholesale
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the listen only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes
should you need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star
then 0 on your touchstone phone
please note that this conference is
being recorded
i now hand the conference over to mr
bhargav dasgupta
md and ceo icici lombard general
insurance limited
thank you and over to you sir thank you
steve
and good evening everybody and thank you
for uh
joining the earnings conference call of
icc lombard
for q4 fy 2020 and for the full year
of 2020. so i would like to give you
a brief overview of the recent
developments in the industry
and our responses to them post which our
cfo mr gopal balachandran will share the
financial performance of the company
now as we speak today we are operating
in unprecedented times
the kovit 19 pandemic has disrupted
every aspect of our life
at the last count the virus has affected
210 countries across the globe as far as
india is concerned timely measures taken
by the state
such as the countrywide lockdown to
break the transmission chain
calibration of trade and commercial
commerce activity social distancing norm
etc
have helped limit the contagion at the
same time this would lead to
significant economic impact the extent
of which
is not exactly quantifiable at this
stage
now at ics and lombard we have
reorganized ourselves to service our
customers and support our channel
partners while ensuring the safety and
well-being of our employees
we've been able to achieve this thanks
to the technology journey that we have
traversed over
over a decade today our customers can
experience the entire
insurance process from purchase to
policy servicing to claim information to
renewal
in the digital mode right at the
purchase stage we offer multiple options
for
transacting through web mobile apps etc
today about 96.5 of policies issued
by us are in paperless form with regard
to claim settlement we offer multiple
digital solutions for
quick uh processing a case to the point
is intraspect
for motor own damage claims the feature
available on our mobile app does away
with the need to
physically survey the damage vehicle
allowing real real-time claim assessment
and approval uh since its inspection
inception in
2017 we have approved more than six and
a half lakh
claims instantly throughout using
intraspec
during the lockdown we managed to
conduct damage assessment of 100 of the
cases using
inspect on the health insurance front we
introduced an ai enabled claim
settlement engine to authorize some of
the health claims
during the lockdown in april 31 of all
were authorized using uh this tool
for policy servicing and query
resolution we are encouraging our
customers to make use of our digital
solutions among the lockdown
we have experience that more than 50 of
the customers calling the call center
prefer to opt
for our digital platforms when given the
option to do do so
we are heartened by this response to the
same as we look ahead we will continue
to promote our digital
services available 24 by 7 to our
customers
now going beyond customers support we've
been pursuing ways to truly
address customer needs in these
challenging times we introduce a
dedicated product coving 19
protection cover that provides 100 or
some insured on the first diagnosis of
the virus
we have offered this relevant
proposition across channels
including entering the tie ups with
entities such as flipkart bars pay et
cetera to
reach their customer base now amazon's
log
lockdown obtaining medical advice is a
big challenge
so harnessing our health ecosystem and
the technological prowess
we've introduced the teleconsult feature
on our mobile app i'll take care
within four months since its launch in
january 2020 we have seen a surge in
utilization of this
facility the app that was first
introduced to corporate customers
in witnessed an increase of more than 50
during the lockdown
uh among its this base further the app
is being rolled out to our
entire retail customer base it will
enable us to expand our scope of
wellness
and other value-added offerings to
customers going
beyond addressing their insurance
purchase claim intimation and query
servicing needs
engaging with customers beyond business
is critical in these times
we introduced several initiatives
including online webinars to help
customers stay positive cyber safe and
engaged
each of these sessions witnessed
participation of over 4 000 customers
further for corporate customers we've
conducted focus sessions in
involving eminent professionals from the
healthcare space and our senior members
to discuss
on relevant risk and insurance aspects
we reached out to more than three and a
half thousand corporate and sme clients
in the process turning to our channel
partners as you know our
diverse distribution setup forms a key
component of our competitive
strength uh over the years we've
deployed technology solutions to equip
our channel partners with the right
tools to conduct business
and service their customers in these
trying times they're try ensuring
customer retention becomes an important
growth
level for our channel partners to help
them in their retention efforts we have
deployed the latest technological tools
for example uh robocalling and crm tools
for motor dealer partners
we've also activated our remote work
from home call center for this purpose
further we have encouraged increased
users usually of digital tools like mira
and ipartner for sourcing and servicing
customers
while many of our partners were already
using these tools some of them require
handholding
we've we have conducted training
programs for these partners to
familiarize them with these tools and
guide them to
on other challenges being faced i think
the uh
during this lockdown more than four and
a half thousand channel partners have
gained
from our online webinars conducted by
senior leaders
april may are the months when we run a
focused campaign called uran for the sme
segment
this year despite the contrary and
constraints we have launched this
initiative through our multiple digital
platforms positioning it as digital
run this approach has yielded results as
we have witnessed 89 percent of business
sourcing
through our digital solutions during the
lockdown for this segment
even as we work towards supporting our
customers and channel partners we've
been ensuring the safety and well-being
of our employees
in fact we had taken steps on this front
in early march
uh much before the lockdown at our key
office setups we had introduced social
distancing norms use of sanitizers and
deployed screening equipment
to monitor employee health as we moved
to a complete work from home scenario
post the national lockdown our
technology solutions and remotely
deployable iit infrastructure has helped
us in maintaining service continuity
today our employees have the right tools
to operate and collaborate with
colleagues across more than 250 branch
offices and virtual office locations
further we have been engaging with our
employees in multiple ways
during this time we accelerate our
efforts towards upskilling our employees
by leveraging
technology platforms in this regard we
introduced e-learning programs
self-consumption videos and scheduling
live training events
over 3200 learning hours were consumed
through e-learning modules
further employees were given access to
987 videos with 150 plus hours of
learning content
on our video portal k point for those
requiring requiring special assistance
we have scaled up our internal air
platform such as sun to learn which
provides online counselling
while ensuring well-being and
productivity of our employees given the
unprecedented scenario the management
committee the senior most
you know level of the organization has
decided to forego 50
of his annual bonus of fy 2020 and
salary increment for fi 2021
in order to contain the expense of
management
at ics lombard we are committed to
support the efforts of policy makers
and the society in containing the impact
of the pandemic
as part of our csr commitment we have
contributed to icsa group support of
rupees 1 billion towards initiatives
aimed at curtailing covet 19 impact
this includes contribution of 500
million to pm care
care fund by our company as well as
voluntary salary
salary donations by our employees with
contributions ranging up to one month
salary donation as well
amounting to 12 million further we have
introduced free covet 19 testing
for the underprivileged sections of the
society for this we have partnered with
reputed diagnostic brands
in addition we have provided you know
personal protection equipment or ppe
in medical to medical staff for treating
copenhagen patients
at certain government hospitals in high
impact cities like mumbai
amid our efforts authority has been
forthcoming and has announced several
measures for the benefit of
policyholders and to ensure smooth
operations of
insurers this includes directing
insurers to simplify claim
procedures ensuring claim authorization
within two hours
etc it has also ensured a swift response
to product approval enabling insurance
insurers like us to introduce dedicated
coven 19 solutions in time
further the authority has been
instrumental in ensuring that
insurance is classified as an essential
service i would also like to touch upon
a few specific announcements by the
regulator
the authority had notified on march 27
2020 that
insurance company shall continue to
charge the prevailing rates for motor
third party liability insurance covers
from april 1 2020
onwards until further order is issued
this will impact the industry loss ratio
adversely for the current year
further in april 16 2020 the authority
announced further relaxation for payment
of premium on renewals for more third
party and
health insurance policies teammate till
may 15 2020.
for the industry this could lead to
short-term impact on premium growth
as customers may choose to renew at a
later date
additionally subdued auto sales in the
last few quarters followed by temporary
shutting of oems are expected to impact
new business sourcing
it would thus be a challenge for the
motor insurance segment to maintain the
desired growth trajectory
in fi 2021. person to uh
regulatory guidelines on food and
management of financial resources
the board of directors have not
recommended final dividend for
fi 2020. in this scenario the interim
dividend
declared by the company will become the
final dividend for fi 2020.
it is important for you to note that
despite the current meltdown we have
demonstrated a strong solvency position
of 2.17 times
as at march 31st 2020 our solvency ratio
continues to be well above the
regulatory minimum of 1.5 times
let me now appraise you uh of the
industry performance in the recently
concluded fiscal year the general
insurance industry registered a growth
of eleven point seven percent
in sy 2020 over fi 2019 with the
industry gdp moving up from
uh 101 893.02 billion in fy 2020
from 1694.48 billion
in fy 2019 as per gi council report
excluding crop segment this growth would
be 10.7
the overall growth and growth excluding
crop segment was 1.7 and 4.3
percent respectively for q for 2020 as
compared to
q4 to fi 2019
the combined ratio for the industry was
112.6
in nine months fi 2020 as compared to
further the overall combined ratio of
the private multi-line general
insurance was 106.5 in nine month fi
as compared to 103.4 percent in nine
month
fi 2019 these numbers are based on
available public disclosures
uh information published on their
respective company websites
excluding national united reliance
health and aditya builder
coming to the outlook for the year ahead
it is extremely difficult to gauge the
exact economic damage
and consequent impact on our industry at
this point
at this you know as such you know giving
a guidance at this stage could be
misleading
having said that i would still like to
share our current view
of how different segments could behave
in the near term
now as far as the commercial lines are
concerned given the increase in rates
for some of the occupancies we expect
the fire port
portfolio to grow reasonably well
however marine and engineering segments
may witness degrowth due to reduced
transit of
consignments and delay in project
commencements
we have also witnessed policy extensions
installments
due to working capital related
constraints group health penetration
should increase given the overarching
health concerns
and the ministry of home affairs
directive on workers
we expect rural segment to witness
faster turnaround post lockdown
as the lockdown is lifted idle plans and
stalled construction projects
may lead to startup risk on resumption
we expect event insurance
credit and liability insurance segments
may see increased claims
demand for pandemic risk cover should
rise as it is currently not prevalent in
order prevailing cover in india
as far as retail lines are concerned
motor portfolio growth
would be would get impacted due to
subdued growth in new vehicle sales
further influenced by the zero hike in
third party premium rates still for the
intimation from the authority
we expect lower impact on agency and
point of sale based
channels due to higher focus on renewal
portfolio
while we are currently experiencing
lower claim incidence in motor portfolio
there could be a surge in claims once
lockdown is lifted
further with with regard to the retail
health indemnity portfolio we expect
subdued growth in q1
fi 2021 in particular we expect health
agency should grow during this period
given our
efforts to build this network over the
last few years talking about the health
benefit of portfolio we expect muted
disbursement in banking nba and hsc
sector
which may have an impact on growth of
this segment
travel segment demand would be most
adversely impacted
on the other hand we expect the sme
channel to continue exhibiting higher
growth
given its move to digital adoption
amidst the current challenging operating
environment we continue to reorient our
business model as the event
unfolds even though this you know
through this unprecedented situation the
fundamentals of our customers
of our company remain strong we are also
preparing to unlock
underlying opportunities that this event
has provided to us
our focus will continue to be creating
value for all our stakeholders through
prudential resellation
harnessing technology and pursuing
sustained profitability
for the long term in spite of the
immediate challenge we remain confident
that the wrong
long-term prospects for the industry
remains robust and in fact may become
even stronger in certain segments
our effort would be to
disproportionately benefit from any
long-term positives that may emerge for
the industry
i will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently
concluded quarters uh thanks bhagav
and good evening everyone hope everyone
is staying safe and healthy
i will now give you a brief overview on
the financial performance of the company
for the quarter
and the year ended master tv 2020 we
have put up the results presentation on
our website
you can access it as we walk you through
the performance numbers
gross direct premium income of the
company's two diet rupees 133.13 billion
in fy 2020
as compared to rupees 144.88 billion in
a day growth of 8.1 percent excluding
the crop segment
our gdpr increased to rupees 133.02
billion in fy 2020
as compared to 120.36 billion in fi 2019
registering a growth of 10.5 percent
this was in line with the industry
growth
excluding crop segment the gdp growth
was 2.9
in quarter 4 fy 2020 over quarter four
fy 2090
as compared to industry growth of 4.3
percent for the same period
our gdpr growth was primarily driven by
our focus on preferred segments such as
fire
health motor marine and liability
consequent to the increase in minimum
prescribed rates for certain occupancies
under fire segments
this segment registered a healthy gdpi
growth of 42.9
in fy 2020 thereby aiding the gdpa
growth of our property and
casualty segment as indicated in our
results presentation the overall
property and casualty segment grew by
twenty point four percent in fy 2020 or
fi 2019
on the retail side of the business sme
and agency channel
and health indemnity continue to grow
faster
and remain our area of focus to harness
the potential of these segments
we have been expanding our distribution
network to increase penetration entire
three and tier four cities
our individual agents including the
point of sale distribution
where 47 548 as on mars 31 2020
as against 35729 as on march 31 2019.
the long-term motor penetration for
private cars increased to 19
for the period ended march 31 2020
from 3.6 for the period ended march 31
2019.
and for two wheelers it stood at 15.8
percent for the period ended mass 31
from 28.8 for the period ended mass 31
the advanced premium was 30.25 billion
as at mass 31 2020
from 13.24 billion as at mass 31 2019
combined ratio stood at 100.4 in fy 2020
as compared to 98.8 percent in fbi 2019
privately on account of long-term motor
policies
change in product mix and losses from
catastrophic
events combined ratio shoot at 100.1
percent in quarter four twenty twenty
as compared to ninety nine percent in
quarter four f by twenty ninety
our investment assets rose to rupees to
sixty three point two seven billion
at mass thirty one twenty twenty as
compared to rupees to forty eight point
four five billion
at december 31 2019. our investment
leverage
net of borrowing borrowings was 4.21
times at mass 31 2020
as compared to 4.16 times at december 31
2019.
investment income increased to rupees
18.47 billion in fy 2020
as compared to rupees 17.55 billion fbi
on a quarterly basis investment income
decreased to rupees four point zero six
billion in quarter four fy 2020
as compared to rupees 4.14 billion in
quarter four fy 2019
investment income of quarter four fy
2020 and
f the full year 2020 included impairment
on
equity investment assets of rupees 1.2
billion
as per its policy consequent to market
volatility at the end of the year
resulting from uncertainties and impact
of kovit 19 event
our capital gains including the
impairment
of equity investment assets was lower at
rupees 1.99 billion in fy 2020
as compared to rupees 4.25 billion in
fbi 2019
capital gains again including the
impairment on equity investment assets
in quarter
4 fy 2020 was at a negative rupees 0.25
billion
as compared to rupees 0.56 billion in
quarter 4
fbi 2019 as a company we have always
exhibited tighter internal exposure
norms as against regulatory limits
on the fixed income side we continue to
focus on safety
liquidity and returns in that order of
priority
given that we do have a large fixed
income portfolio
including government securities
accordingly we have invested a high
proportion
right 81.7 percent of the debt portfolio
in sovereign or
aaa and above rated security for that we
are focused on the quality of portfolio
on this front we have zero exposure of
our fixed income portfolio and
securities rated
below double a we do not have a single
instance of delayed interest
or default over the last 19 years
we will continue to adopt a disciplined
approach in terms of the investments
that we make
our profit before tax grew by six point
two percent to
rupees 16.97 billion in nfi 2020 as
compared to rupees 15.98 billion in fbi
whereas profit before tax grew by 7.3 to
rupees 3.71 billion in q4 2020
as compared to rupees 3.45 billion and
q4 for 2019.
as stated in the previous quarter's
earnings calls
the company has elected to exercise the
option of lower income tax rate
the effective tax rate was 29.7 percent
in fbi 2020
and 23.9 percent in quarter for fy 2020.
consequently profit after tax grew by 13
to rupees 11.94 billion in fy 2020
as compared to rupees 10.49 billion in
fbi 2019
whereas profit after tax grew by 23.8
percent to raise 2.8 billion
82 billion in quarter 4 2020 as compared
to rupees 2.28 billion in quarter
four 2019 return on average equity was
20.8 percent in fy 2020
as compared to 21 21.3 percent in fi
2019 the return on average equity for
quarter 4
20 20 was 18.8 percent as compared to
17.5 percent in quarter four for 2019
solvency ratio was 2.17 times at mass 31
as against 2.18 times at december 31
continued to be higher than the minimum
regulatory requirement of 1.5 times
as we conclude our address i would like
to summarize that we ended
quarter 4 fy 2020 and the full year 2020
with a diversified product portfolio and
healthy financials
the company continues to focus on
student underwriting while improving its
competitive positioning
further we remain focused on enhancing
our digital capabilities
and drive the agenda of sustainable
growth i would like to thank you all for
attending our
earnings conference call and we would be
happy to take any specific questions
that you may have
thank you very much we will now begin
the question and answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question you
may press star and one on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to remove yourself from the
question queue you may press star into
participants are requested to use
sunsets for asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
the first question is from the line of
suresh ganpati from macquarie
please go ahead yeah hi uh
you know i know it's x yeah hi uh bdg so
you know i know it is a very very tough
environment
and difficult to give any guiding and
there are several
moving parts here but if i were to
really look at your combined operating
ratio
considering that there will be losses in
third party and there is a certain
operating leverage in the motor business
how do you see this spanning our bdg
would it increase from
say 100.4 percent directionally we just
want to
for financial 2021 or do you think there
is a possibility that you can contain it
because currently the claim experience
is favorable right i mean because there
are lower accident claims and stuff so
can it
offset the negative impact coming from
covet 19
yeah so first this is genuinely a very
tough question to answer at this point
in time because as you rightly said
there are many moving parts
and there are changes that are coming in
from
quarters that you didn't anticipate ever
in your planning exercise
um having said that when we look at uh
our current view looking at the
situation today unless there are some
unpleasant surprises that we haven't we
couldn't anticipate
on balance given the positives and
negatives that you yourself have
articulated
plus what i talked about in terms of
some claims increases that we see plus
the fact that db
won't happen also the frequency of games
right now are lower
on balance we believe that we should be
able to continue to deliver on our
objective of keeping the combined around
even for this year but as i said i this
is very very difficult to give a
guidance
it is only you know you should look at
this as
our estimate currently this estimate can
very easily change
uh soon if the underlying
reality changes that we haven't been
able to anticipate
and one more question is in the group
health where you are seeing a reasonable
amount of demand
would you really think this could be a
profitable product proposition because
maybe at the individual level of course
the product is far more profitable than
really focusing at the group level
look if you see what we've been doing
relative to the
industry mix so if you see the
industry's mix of
health the composition of growth and
group health
for the industry is roughly about fifty
percent yeah which is a corporate
employee employee
segment uh shared lower than fifty maybe
fourteen something
uh for us that number is roughly around
thirty seven
uh which tells you that you know and you
know our approach right so we are
focusing on we always focus on building
a
uh sustainable portfolio so generally
group health has been uh
uh you know a segment which has been
difficult in terms of
uh pricing uh in the marketplace
so that the point is anyway valid the
point that you're making
so having said that in this environment
one should expect a bit more reasonable
approach on underwriting from the
marketplace
if at all we find pricing being sensible
then we would look out look at it
if it is not then we will remain uh you
know cautious the way we've been
operating what we've been doing even
when you're looking at that share
of the mix that i talked about our
approach has been
go granular focus on the smes mid market
small uh
clients not go for the big ticket uh you
know policies from bfsi or
uh or it companies huge employee base
where the competitive pressure drives
the premium down to a level which is not
sustainable
so we've not been anywhere winning any
of this uh you know
contracts and we have deliberately let
them be
for others see that approach and the
philosophy will continue
we will see how it plays out in terms of
pricing so in terms of the
price changes needed because of covet
that is of course a bit of a modeling
that we are doing
and like millions of models that are
floating around it makes a lot of
assumptions on what will happen to the
number of people who get infected in
india
and there is that element of risk that
we are carrying
okay and finally one last question is on
the investment
book you know i mean if you were to look
at globally the interest rates are
really heading uh
and you know structurally it looks like
it's going to be a very
low interested environment globally i
don't know how long it will be
sustainable
in this environment you know your roe of
course has always been pretty good in 20
plus range wouldn't that be at risk
because of structurally
lower investment returns considering the
way the interest rates are heading
or likely to head in future so this has
been true
even before this event um and
uh you know we can also have a long
debate on what this could do
macroeconomically over a longer period
of time as the global supply chain gets
disrupted what it does to inflation
while these central banks will obviously
drive
uh down to uh lower levels but
it's again you know very very
speculative to estimate what will happen
to interest rates one or two years into
the future
our approach has been showing 20 years
we've seen cycles
we would want to continue to focus on
delivering on the roe
if we believe that interest rates are
going down to a level which is not
sustainable
we would want to improve the combine of
course that depends on the market uh
condition in terms of the competitive
intensity i think on competitive
intensity we believe
this event could potentially strengthen
the stronger
simply because of uh you know the
balance sheets
that some of the companies have built
over the years the solvency cushion that
we have
also the digital uh leadership that we
have in the market we should help us
but i think the point that you're making
remains valid in any scenario because
today we are talking about a scenario
which is very very unpredictable
thank you thank you for watching thank
you
a reminder to the participants please
limit your questions to participant
should you have any follow-up request to
rejoin the queue please
the next question is from the line of
mary mw from jpmorgan
please go ahead uh yes thank you for the
opportunity
and then thank you so much for your the
very excellent
presentation i have a two questions
one is about your technology side
now it seems to be at a pretty tough
time for the
every industry it means that overall the
not only the marketing the claim and on
the writing probably very challenged as
well
so the my question is how do you rate
the company's technology
in both claim adjustment and on the
writing perspective
compared to the industry and then the
second question
is about the specific underwriting
so still the overall the underwriting
related with the factory insurance
probably relatively small
but the the core vision 19 seems to be
the major
the pandemic globally so i just want to
know whether
any concern we should have relate to the
business in production coverage
so any update on this appreciate it
thank you
okay let me take the second one first
and then i'll answer the first questions
uh on the second one
uh you know there are two types of bi
covers which you know you
know there are uh you know bi that
triggers on our damage material damage
and there are non-damage bi which gets
triggered without a material damage like
you know let's say triggered by a
pandemic in india there is no
ndbi that has policies in the market so
all the bi policies that we write are
with a
trigger of a material damage and
pandemic is an exclusion
so uh contractually we don't see any
risk
i'm sure you're aware what is happening
globally on this matter but from a
contractual perspective we don't see a
risk
uh coming to your first question uh i
think that's a great one
and you know honestly the way we see it
is that some of the capabilities that
we've built i talked about the sourcing
side
in terms of the fact that today we
launched uh
you know for the smes this these are two
big months of uh you know policy
procurement
and we could uh launch our initiative
which we do you know
every year as a digital initiative and
89 of policies we've sourced digitally
and the sme business has grown in this
period
uh and that probably tells you the
uh digital capability that we've built
on the
claim side and that's probably the most
impor interesting aspect that we've
talked about
there are lots of elements that we've
built on the retail side we keep talking
about
uh i talked about the uh instaspect uh
the you know visual uh
the virtual in you know inspection that
we do
today as of now in this lockdown phase
100 of motor claims that are getting
paid are
uh are getting settled are using uh you
know that capability
similarly the ai based uh you know
health insurance claims what are the
corporate side
you know this has been a period where
we've done a lot of innovative uh
you know work and i'll talk about couple
of them and i'll then
ask alok to add anything that he may
want to add
so on the on the risk inspection side we
started virtual risk
you know assessment uh we you know we
are doing a video based
uh risk assessment uh virtually without
having to send our risk inspection
inspectors in we are providing remote
risk advisory on plant operation we
anyway have a
team of specialists who provide risk
advisory
we are doing that remotely we
provide iot iot based monitoring tools
not a very large number of customers who
use some of these solutions but the ones
that are using it
are getting triggers sitting at home uh
so similarly you've done
you know drone based loss survey in this
period
to help customers allocate you have
anything else that you want to add
yeah apart from the value added services
that you mentioned on the claim
side what we have done is on the basis
of virtual documents
we have started settling claims yes it
has helped in reducing the
backlog of claims tremendously
just to give you a sense of the number
of policies for example this
knockdown period using the chatbot or
the email what
you know what do you call it the rpa
solution that we have
uh yeah we've been able to issue
more than 40 000 policies and these are
corporate policies
yeah i think that's very clear um so
just want to confirm so are you very
optimistic on the companies the
the the market share gaining or the
the market positioning after kobe 19
because that
the experience for example china korea
and other many developed markets this
strong the innovation
seemed to give more opportunity for the
for the company so
i'm just one want to get some color how
the management to think about the
company's future
after the kobe 19 then we remain
very uh you know optimistic relative to
the other players in the market
as i said we are you know definitely
uh cautious about the larger environment
and what it will do
to the economic growth and consequently
insurance business
but within that as i said right in my
opening address
we should be able to benefit
disproportionately because of some of
these points that we made
uh innovation technology capability as
also balance sheet strength
thank you so much that's very clear
appreciate
thank you
the next question is from the line of
shire shivani from clsa india private
limited please go ahead
hi thank you for the opportunity uh sir
i had one question regarding
um so so there was an aid regulation not
a regulation but there was a committee
set up which is going to
talk about uh indemnity-based health
products to be sold by life insurers as
well
so i want to understand how uh how this
will
impact uh the general insurance industry
or isis lombard as such
specifically and do you see because of
this the price competition going ahead
and
you know the product becoming less
competitive for you guys to
keep growing at the in it the way you've
been growing and
also second thing which i wanted to
understand because you have a group
company which is also doing
which is which which will get uh the
license to do indemnity health if it die
approves it
how does that affect like what kind of
uh
can you throw some light on that how
does that affect your uh group
uh strategy etc so um
the let me probably answer the third one
first because that's
separate from the response to the list
you know wherever there are segments of
business where we have similar products
like for health benefit
we compete in the marketplace and that's
how it is and
if this happens in the in the industry
side we would also compete in the
marketplace we wouldn't worry about that
uh coming back to the larger question
that you're asking uh
yes the committee has been formed but
the committee
as far as i know couldn't meet because
of all of this i don't believe that
meeting has happened unless in this
lockdown period a virtual meeting has
happened that i'm not aware of so the
committee has to come together and
give the report we'll have to wait for
the report that the committee gets
if you having said that while we don't
know what the committee will say
uh if you step back uh till about
2015-16
uh there was no such uh separation um
the life companies were allowed to
uh write uh you know all types of help
and in fact
we as an industry we as a company wanted
to the right long-term health which we
were not uh
you know allowed to at that point in
time the separation came at that point
in time
it wasn't as if in those days also the
life companies were doing a lot of
health indemnity business and let me get
into the uh
the spec you know elements of that
business as i said if you look at the
overall
health business roughly 50 percent of
almost 50 percent of the business comes
from group health
now in group health
typically we offer a bouquet of
solutions to corporates which has fire
which has marine which is liability
and we offer you know that bunch now
logically there shouldn't be any
big competitive advantage that a health
life company may have unless they want
to undercut further
you know that is one area and if they
want to do that that's a that's a choice
but generally we won't expect that to be
a sustainable strategy
so large part of the volume of business
comes from group health
and we as an industry have scaled up
that
you know that business including
managing the
you know using that flow to manage the
network uh
and the other thing that you have to
realize that apart from distribution
capability there has to you have to have
many other capabilities on the health
side
uh to be able to compete um be it in
terms of
in-house claim service i mean you know
we took claim service in-house in 2008.
there is some capability and technology
advantage that we've built for example
the ai based
claim solution that i talked about uh
you can start writing health insurance
on the retail side using a tpa
but i don't know if that really helps in
terms of building these capabilities
so that's uh that's number one number
two if you see the approach that we are
taking
even if let's say life companies do come
in the airport that we are taking
if you see what we've been talking about
on the ielts take care
is really taking health insurance to
another level
of providing complete solution to uh you
know people so for example in this
lockdown period on the
i'll take care app we have a feature for
our corporate clients where
you can do a tele uh consultation with
doctors and
we have a dedicated uh you know a
partnership which uh you know delivers
it
uh that piece we've now opened up for
all our customers
uh you don't necessarily have to be a
health customer and that's you know
really picked up
uh you know at this point in time now
these are capabilities that we've built
over the over the years in terms of
network into the ecosystem in terms of
technology in terms of data
analytics if someone is able to come in
and compete
so be it we wouldn't really worry about
that competition
having said that we don't know if the
regulator will allow it we'll have to
wait for the committee report
okay great thank you so much that was it
thank you the next question is from the
line of dignity
from mk global please go ahead
yeah hi and uh thanks for the facility
uh
um i just wanted uh you to you know
re-confirm the kind of uh i mean uh
elaborate a little
further on your opening remarks that you
talked about the good
the future was perfect from individual
segments
uh from fire to the health and all if
you get a little bit a little
a little detail into it wherever you say
that you know where you're expecting
uh fire to grow well whereas marine to
you know slow down and all
so that segment if we can elaborate once
again a little a little bit
detailed or uh granularity that would be
really helpful
yeah we can i can do that in a granular
manner but it will be very difficult to
predict
or give any guidance on where we see the
numbers for obvious seasons
so if you look at the corporate segment
the larger segments are
fire where we've had price increases
during this year
and last year and corporate customers
generally don't want to keep their
assets uninsured so the b2b segment i
think largely will be uh
protected now within that fire will
should grow
it should have a positive growth this
year the rest of it is a bit of a
uncertain uh you know picture because
for example marine transit which is
uh what you you know where you ensure uh
you know
the logistics chain that obviously is
stalled as of now now how do we
predict a number if you don't know when
uh
you know a red zone will become an
orange and when an orange zone will
become green
so even when we are planning for numbers
on a day-to-day basis we are reviewing
it very very frequently
uh you know internally within our teams
uh
having said that we probably couldn't
anticipate
this extension this quarterly you know
the in this month
now we don't know what will happen 15
days from now so it's very difficult to
give you a sense of what these numbers
will be for the year
uh what we've decided is that we will
watch it i mean every part of our
business we are basically looking at
what is happening on a daily basis
we've completely changed our dashboards
of monitoring the business
uh in this period right from even before
we went into work from home as a whole
company we realized that you know this
is a big thing that is happening so we
completely change our dashboard so all
we are doing is
staying very close to the ground to see
what is happening and
uh reacting to it in terms of uh in
terms of seizing any opportunity that we
that we see so but on balance what we
are saying fire we think will be
positive marriage
would be negative uh you know
engineering would be negative
now extent of negative we can say for
this quarter definitely negative
thereafter we don't know
um liability you know i've talked about
the two
key ones liability i think should be uh
okay um
motor and health health should do well
uh though in this quarter it may be a
bit
slow uh but overall for the year it
should do okay
do reasonably okay motor will be
affected it again depends on when
uh you know dealerships are open and new
vehicle sales comes
now again on new vehicles let's assume
you know two months from now the whole
country has been opened up and
dealerships are open
can you predict with any level of
confidence the customer psyche at this
point in time
there are two contrary points of view
some of you uh
understand the auto sector as well you
know
one segment believes that uh there will
be no more
uh adoption of personal mobility uh so
people will use vehicles more and so
people may buy more vehicles
at least at the lower end uh there's
another point of view that
uh you know the the amount of travel
itself will come down
so and people won't have discretionary
spending ability
so they will not uh actually buy cards
either one of them can happen and anyone
who
predicts i think is uh
you know at least i wouldn't predict
with any level of conviction
uh so we will have to watch what is
happening rather than be brave and
saying that we know this is
what's going to happen i think it's one
of the most important for us to do is
uh protect the balance sheet uh focus on
risk management
digitize as much as possible so that you
benefit inordinately
and related to the market outperform
that's what we would like to do
okay and it has just confirming that you
said
there will be some acceleration
happening in the group health plan but
you're focusing on a smaller uh
corporate or uh
uh compared to the rit company right
just to make that sizing little more
favorable towards you
no so those large group and pieces we
anyway were avoiding because of
pricing being uh unsustainable even in
the past
i think the point that i was making this
rash is that if the pricing improves uh
you know there is an opportunity if the
pricing doesn't improve we'll stay
focused on the segments that we are
staying focused on which is the mid
market and the sne segment
that sounds great thanks thanks a lot
sir and all of us
thank you thank you the next question is
from the lineup bharat shah from esk
investment
please go ahead uh uh
with his positive paintings
[Music]
would provide any tailgrain for the
industry over a period of time
and how have you uh have you rethought
any part or
hold of the business uh based on the
kovid event
uh is a future strategy
so you know we believe this will be in
the long term positive for the gi
uh events like this uh make people more
aware of the risks uh that we have uh
it's unfortunate
that's the nature of our industry but
when things like these things happen
people realize the importance of risk
management uh and protection so
uh in the and particularly if you look
at the health uh insurance uh
you know space uh even when stars
happened post that
in hong kong health insurance you know
demand went up naturally so on balance
we believe this will be positive for the
gi industry in a
medium term in the short term it will be
very it
if a lot of the top line will disappear
because i think all companies and right
now must be degrowing
at this stage um particularly driven by
motor uh in terms of approach
uh as i said what we are trying to do is
we are
we are enabling
all our the entire part of our
organization and the extended arm which
is our
distributors to enable them to do as
much of business as they can
from uh from home uh using tools using
training etc that we're talking about
and actually we are kind of opening up a
bit more segments to do business than
what we were earlier willing to
particularly
let's say motor insurance you know even
in healthier
uh you know going very very uh
focused in terms of scaling up the
business particularly into the internet
etc
so it's not a big change in segments of
business
uh but the focus is in terms of the
renewal
the old book and how do we get a higher
share of the market using our digital
capabilities
uh sanjeev you want to add anything more
to what i just said
no absolutely right and also just to
mention you know
before last we had added virtual offices
across the country
and that has hold held us good even in
the the month which is just gone by
april
the drop is there but relatively low
there's still some bit of activity in
those regions so we will
probably use what you also have stated
the
the extensive physical reach also that
we had created through virtual offices
across the country will hold us good in
the time to come
okay and secondly is
the fixed income and the equity ratio
of the total investment book is on 31st
december
19 and 31st march 20.
gopal you want to take that yeah sure so
i think on the equity book
i think it cost as on 31st december 2019
the holding would be about 10 of the
overall investments will be
uh into equities that cost that number
at the end of 31st march uh 2020 is at
about 10.9
so roughly about 11 or so and the rest
of the book is
largely uh split on la for
primarily on the fixed income portfolio
between uh government securities and
uh corporate books and would you have
that number
basement for market value in those two
days
i think from a market value perspective
which is what we mentioned as a part of
the opening remarks
if you have looked at the mark to market
impact on the equity portfolio
uh as at the reporting date i am giving
this number uh
before the provision for impairment that
we took on the equity assets
the mark-to-market loss on the equity
portfolio was roughly about
550 crores as at that reporting date
but we took over impairment also
liquid funds but we also you know
largely use
the traps market but uh all the
fixed income positions is directly hit a
little bit exposure is uh some liquid
funds little bit here and there
and when last month over the period of
time one of the participants that we are
asked
when they do sex income written it looks
uh almost certain that over a period of
time
they will diminish and if you have to
protect
return on equity would you not consider
apart from
of course improving combined ratio that
you answered
improving equity allocation in the total
investment
book you know absolutely if you
see we've been kind of reducing our
equity allocation
excuse me over the last three four years
uh
in a sense we were a bit concerned about
the
the valuations and in this period in the
month of
march early april we increased
allocation a little bit
but the market ran up much faster than
what we expected
again we don't know if this is
sustainable but
you guys will know that better than us
but we would want to increase
equity allocation what we are doing is
we are certain
so we keep evaluating certain companies
that we like and if it comes within our
range of price we you know increase our
allocation it's not as if we have a
fixed
uh view on that we want to increase it
to x percentage we
go stock specific uh and actually in
this period we've increased the
allocation a little bit not to the
extent that we would have liked to
uh but we've increased allocation so we
would do that
the other point to uh you know remember
is even in this period when the market
flows up
uh in the month in march some extremely
high quality corporate names
yields went up uh tremendously
and that was a period where we even on
the fixed income side
we locked in some of these uh you know
high quality corporate names and even
from a duration perspective we just
added some a little bit there
and that i believe is going to help us
in the long term
uh what you have to realize is that
it is an incremental book let's assume
that the interest rate you know stays at
six percent
you know for 10 years and uh
let's say you know triple a spread is 50
basis point or 60 billion whatever it is
it's
the incremental flow that we have to
invest at that level the old stock
remains
uh we if since the rate comes down we
have a large mark to market positive
i mean we would have a large market
market positive on the bond side
we would decide if you want to take
those profits
based basis the view of that we have in
terms of interest rates
and we've generally been contrarian i
mean you know
about a year and a half back where
everyone was saying interest rates will
go through the roof oil etc we went long
and that call played out so again at
this point in time i would be foolish to
predict where it is going to go
one year from now but we will watch it
very closely and we will
take the right call
but strategically
sorry to interrupt but for any follow-up
request to rejoin the qp
a reminder to the participants please
limit your questions to dopa
participants
should you have any follow-up request to
join the queue please
the next question is from the line of
ajax frederick from bnk securities
please go ahead thanks for the
opportunity sir
sir uh the commission uh payout has
increased dramatically for
the quarter uh so order of that
sorry the what went up i couldn't get
your question
commission commission gopal you have the
answer
so uh jokes i think it is purely i think
if you're referring to the
are you referring to the net commission
ratio yeah
also so when you look at the next net
commission ratio i think
ajax is obviously a function of one what
kind of business mix that you write
across the portfolio of businesses that
we write
one in that you will kind of split the
net commissions in terms of commissions
paid which is what we kind of incur for
sourcing businesses
and the second element is more of an
income that accrues to us which is by
virtue of the
reinsurance commissions that we earn
with respect to the portfolio that we
would be doing in terms of risk transfer
now in this quarter when you look at
when you look at the breakdown
uh in so far as the commission paid or
let's say the acquisition ratio is
concerned there is not
much of a moment in terms of what you
see
but in quarter four what as what we
explained as a part of the
opening remarks some of the health uh
benefit portfolio is something that we
have not
seen as much growth as what we would
have expected it to be
and that part of the business is
something that we kind of also
we have been historically uh reinsuring
and to that extent the extent of
commission income that we would have
earned on that part of the business is
relatively
lower so hence when you look at the
overall net commission ratio it looks
like there has been an increase
but in so far as the acquisition cost is
concerned it is there is not any
significant change that's one and
secondly i think what we have
always kept looking at is more from a
combined perspective because that would
be a true reflection of
the overall operations of insurance that
we underwrite
and there if you have seen whether it is
for the quarter four or whether it is
for the full year
in line with what we have been uh
articulating also in our earlier
uh years as well as a part of our calls
is to try and sustain
the overall combined at around 100
ah okay and so on uh
renewals so a business wise like motor
and health at least
what proportion is the new business or
how much is renowned
robot you want to give the number so
again if you're looking at your own the
let's say from the motor site for
example um
if you look at roughly we would last
year we would have had almost a 50 50
kind of a mix
for the full year uh 2019 uh new would
have been 50
and renewal would have been uh fifty
percent uh for the current year fi
twenty given that uh the new vehicle
sales have been relatively
uh lower uh in terms of growth uh to
that extent the proportion of new to
renewal so new is about uh 38
and the renewal will be about 62
and one health and on the health part of
the business
i think uh given the fact that i think
we were almost there uh
one of the things that you would have to
look at on the health side for example
on the indemnity side
when you look at the overall intensity
growth
for health the new health indemnity
growth which is what we have also put on
the presentation
deck that's one area we are
significantly focusing on over the last
uh three to four years and the new
health indemnity growth has
grown by about 69 percent and if you
would have looked at
because that's on a relatively smaller
base which is why the number looks to be
69 70 growth rate the overall
health portfolio again on the individual
side has grown by about 37 percent
the renewal book has grown at about 17
okay okay another uh just a final
question
uh sorry to interrupt sir but for any
follow-up request to join the queue
please
yes okay thank you the next question is
from the line of nadesh from invest
capital please go ahead uh thanks for
the opportunity sir
so firstly on the reserve releases uh
this year also i think we have seen a
decent present releases last year also
we saw a good reservation
so when we are looking at the fourier
profitability how should we
look at these reserve releases and
whether we should expect them to be
sustainable in future
look the exact release will obviously
depend on our actual
uh analysis that we keep carrying out
monthly and quarterly
uh but the principle remains the same
when we
uh i think kopala has been talking about
do you english over the over the
you know quarters that we when we
reserve we
are conservative about reserving and
because we don't know how
whether all our assumptions will play
out and that's the right approach that
most
uh you know quality insurance companies
do across the world
and over the periods if the actual trend
proves to be in line with or rather
better than what we had anticipated we
would have had some releases
so if you look at our reserve releases
we would exact quantum we can never
predict that next year to be so much
but we should continue to have some
amount of reservability if we continue
with the same strategy
and our strategy and our conservatism in
terms of reserving hasn't changed
shortly and then secondly
going into the next year our top line
growth may remain
uh slightly subdued uh in that
environment uh how much flexibility we
have from our operating expense
perspective and also we have seen a
decent expense of management
allocation which you have to do from
shareholder account which means that
probably in some line of businesses we
were not able to uh
our objects was higher than what
regulatory required
yeah so the second one is gopal to
answer but in terms of the first one
if you see the the true fixed cost i
mean you know if you look at expense
ratio there is a distribution cost which
is the commission that we pay
and a true operating cost which is the
innocence fixed
nothing is fixed but that is kind of
fixed cost
uh if the top line and that number is
actually you know
kind of a single digit number the the
operating cost
so if you see the element of the
sourcing cost if a top line goes down
that will also
go down for us also what we are doing is
we are looking at all our costs with a
fine tooth comb
and we believe from the longer term
perspective obviously right now we are
going through a certain phase but we
believe
there are huge learnings that we've got
out of this you know last one month
experience which we would want to
continue to leverage
in you know as we go along we would want
to become 100
digital company we would want to have 50
of our employees work from home
even in the foreseeable future so these
are things that we are kind of working
on and we are working on those plans
for future it may not have an immediate
benefit in terms of
uh operating cost but in the longer term
it should give us some
leverage but honestly for us the out of
the combined ratio
that part is a relatively small part as
i explained the
real large number is in the claims ratio
and the distribution cost gopal if you
want to add anything to that and answer
the second question
sure i think i will answer the second
question uh
so nidhish i think when you look at as a
company
we have always wanted to ensure
compliance to regulations in so far as
expense of management
is concerned so in that regard as a
company we have been in absolute
compliance to
the regulatory requirement which is on
an aggregate basis where they
expect every company to be within those
limits on expense of management
but your point is correct there is
always an element of
expense allocation that happens across
sub segments
which is also what is laid down by
regulation
and as per the requirement if in any of
the sub segments
bases the allocation of expenses that
happens to each of those
lines of businesses in case if there is
uh any
sub-segment that exceeds the limit that
has been laid down
to that extent the excess of those
expenses is required to be
born out of the shareholders fund and
that is exactly what we have done
but on an aggregate basis as a company
the attempt has been
always to make sure that we are in
compliance with the
overall limit that has been laid down in
so far as regulations are concerned
and just to add on i think one other
point which is something that we have
spoken about also on the
in the past just to add to what bhagav
said uh one should also be equally
mindful of the fact that when it comes
to fixed costs
uh one of the things that we have been
telling over the last couple of quarters
in particular
is the acquisition of the crm platform
that we did
in quarter three and now that obviously
entails
uh some element of fixed cost in the
form of depreciation
that kind of comes through uh over a
quarter on quarter but the impact in
terms of revenue
uh this is the uh uh expectations that
we had already factored in
as a part of uh buying the crm platform
that would happen over a period of three
to four years now in that regard
the platform that we have we had
acquired in quarter three
again has been kind of uh progressing
very well
uh in terms of the expectations that we
would have said yeah in fact
in these times of uncertainties we have
actually been able to deploy that crm
platform quite effectively
and we have been able to do it when we
kind of also indicated as a part of the
introductory remarks
that we have been able to do a lot of
robocalling and
other related aspects to ensure
continuity of
customers for renewability of their
policies
we have actually been able to use this
platform to our uh
advantage sanji we want to add to what
this
gopal just said
and when we picked up in october it was
more of you know from our
systems we've used to go to the dealer
and offer this platform in the current
situation
the stated are even full demand from
their side they also want this to be
installed you'll be happy to note that
in
april when actually you know things have
been
not accessed we have been able to
activate almost 67 dealers
to dealers will become part of the
platform so we are very excited and
this should go a long way in terms of
strengthening our relationship with the
dealers
as well as helping them to reach out
their customers for the renewals which
will be the key thing
at least for quarter one in a big way
thank you the next question is from the
lineup rishi jinjunwala from
iifl please go ahead yeah
thanks for the opportunity couple of
questions one is
uh can you elaborate what is the policy
regarding
um you know recognition of equity
impairment
um because if you really look at it uh
you know
at 120 crores almost five percent of
what your
equity would have been as of the end of
previous quarters so
is it spread across just you know uh is
it only regarding one stock or you know
how do you how do you arrive at that and
what are the chances of that
recovering back and secondly uh on the
health side you mentioned that because
of your probable shift
from uh benefit to indemnity uh
the reinsurance commissions have come
off
uh is this something which is uh
tactical for the short term or
should we take it as a as a long term
trend and as a result
um you know the overall profitability on
that segment
uh could be under pressure considering
um you know there was
pretty heavy reinsurance commission that
we used to receive
uh so let me answer the first one and uh
and i'll cover a bit of the second one
and ask sanjeev to elaborate on that
in terms of the impairment we have a
policy
this is not a requirement but we have a
policy as a matter of prudence
where we test for impairment when uh
there is a substantial for a fall in
market price of security
below our acquisition cost now this is
obviously something that happened in the
uh month of march when the market uh
fell as much as it did
and we do an assessment whether the fall
in price is uh
temporary permanent whether there is a
online change
in the uh intrinsic value of the
of the investment of the investing
company and if we
believe that it is uh prudent to take
a kind of impairment to uh to reflect
the change in the fair value of the
investment company or industry company
then we take an impairment
as a matter of prudence we need not but
we do that
so that's something that we've tested
this time and uh
it's not one company there are a you
know few companies that we've taken a
call on
and adjusted the value uh to what we
believe is a
uh fair uh value now uh
you know it is not as if we believe so
if you believe that us
a stock is uh you know in a sense
something that will not deliver returns
in the future we would exit as you would
sell and exit
and you know maybe gradually we've done
that over there even
during the year we exited some of the
print media stocks
uh we took the loss and we took it
because we didn't see a future there
uh but these are not uh stocks that we
believe that
uh we will not get returns in the future
so we've taken a
put in uh it's a it's a potential call
in terms of taking that
hit now in terms of the second question
that
you have you know obviously it's not a
tactical call to shift out of benefit
we like the benefit business but you
know as i think gopal explained that
the nbc disbursements have went down
in the last quarter and it's been down
for a
fair period and hence the amount of
business that we got from our nbc
partners
we're relatively lower but we are
growing that business elsewhere and i'll
ask sanjeev to uh explain that to you
no clearly i mean we love benefit for
the business and
we've been market leaders in that
particular segment we would love to grow
that
but unfortunately for the last 18 months
as bhargava also mentioned
you know the nbsc sector has gone
through a bit of
tightness in terms of disbursement and
that has impacted it
even in this year with respect to icsa
bank as a bank when they were disbursing
we were able to grow our business with
them in a very reasonable price but the
small
in the nba side was very sharp we are
diversifying we are
you know doing new tie-ups we have done
few
critical tie-ups on the banking side
also last year so we will continue to
uh exploit new opportunities segment and
as in when the turnaround happens our
relationship is very thick with our
partners and we will get rolling on that
front also
great and just quickly on uh uh you know
so clearly we are seeing right down
right now loss ratios in motor segments
going down substantially
uh during the lockdown and on the other
hand uh uh
we have also seen the regulator uh
postponing the hike
in uh motor tp uh for the time being
so just wanted to understand i mean how
do you see that play out at least
for this year and uh do you intend to
reconsider your you know the the
inflation that you've taken
for motor tp uh provisioning uh for this
year
so we will have to watch the numbers you
see i think
you know that's a great question that
you're asking and uh you know this is
something that our actual team will
evaluate
uh you know on an ongoing basis and
obviously if the incurred claims drop to
a level that it
you know drops and stays down uh they
would have to factor some of that into
uh the assumptions but it's really very
difficult to predict what will happen
when things start reopening as i said
there are you know very very logical
and rational views on both sides
in terms of whether people will use
their you know use
vehicles more because of personal
mobility rather than taking public
transport
and with it will it increase claims uh
the jury is out we'll have to watch the
numbers and then take a call
but if it stays down we believe the
the actual team will adjust some of this
all right thank you so much
thank you the next question is from the
line of jamin shah from rwc partners
please go ahead
yeah hi thanks for taking the call
uh two questions one is could you talk a
bit on the government regulation of
compulsory healthcare
insurance and how do you think that
stands out
uh for you and the industry um also you
know
in terms of you know preliminary kind of
queries you get uh
from companies especially on their sunny
side where you are strong and they're
probably not kind of covered
that's question one uh the other
question was more on kind of i wanted to
understand the consumer psychology
here uh you've launched the kovid 19
product quite early
uh who you know who i inquired who were
the buyers
existing customers uh how
how was this kind of you know being kind
of spread because eventually that could
kind of give you a lot more kind of
uh thought process on
you know personal individual health care
kind of as well
um yeah yeah i think sanjiv
you want to take uh the two questions on
the sme and the
and the experience so uh clearly
i'll deploy the covet one first uh
clearly when we launched this product it
was pretty early when things started you
know
building up from an india perspective
where we had a lot of cases coming up
acceptance is very good we have followed
two strategy primarily one is b to b
another is b to b to c you know where uh
we've also
gone and offered these options from the
corporation of the smes wanted to cover
their employees
and their families and they're also in a
much bigger way giving it to b to b to c
player where we have joined hands with
the players who are in the online stream
and they are the ones for offering it to
their customers the initial response has
been very very
encouraging but i must say that we also
are
very closely looking in terms of the
distribution so that we don't have a
concentrated portfolio coming up so
we've done all our cuts and balances
but so far the acceptance and quite
naturally i'm sure each one of us will
agree that
anything on covet service comes in
because it's the imminent risk
evidently we all are living with a
day-to-day basis it becomes a very very
practical way to take a cover on that
while i must also say
the normal integrity cover which each of
the customer has
they're also covered expenses in case of
hospitalization fully covered
on the sme sanji just one let me just
add one point to explain what uh sanji
said so we've
given it to b2 b2c or b2b so as to
eliminate adverse selection risk and we
are also monitoring the portfolio
diversification across the country
so that we don't get into any
concentrated pockets
sanji over t okay yeah thanks uh and
also on the sms side in terms of the
compulsory
health coverage typically on an ongoing
basis you know we do
know that the smaller ghr coverages the
group health coverages have been far
more you know
beneficial from the company side and
we're also able to provide our
exceptional service which you've created
for even larger corporations to smes
we have been going for growing that
portfolio at a reasonable pace of 20 25
we do believe that any progressive
corporate any which way should end up
offering group health so there should be
further demand coming and we will
keep investing it but as bhagavad also
mentioned initially
we have complete clarity that we will
pick up this business
if it makes commercial sense if there is
tremendous
rate war we will probably exchange from
participating in that sort of a business
are you seeing any inquiry etcetera on
that that you want to just touch up on
from your corporate segment on that on
the emergency server
so the worker policy that the government
has made it compulsory from the ministry
of
uh home affairs we are seeing increased
inquiries and there are from the medium
size and large size
corporate especially from construction
side there are a lot of inquiries and a
few policies have been converted
and they are the people who are going
back into
construction of projects and they have
workers
in those areas working but one more
point i want to add
is that most of the com people who
are employing workers have an esi cover
which is applicable for uh for people
earning
rupees 21 000 or below so uh but
that yeah yeah most of the esi hospitals
don't have with the
facilities so therefore covet only
product also they can take for
people uh who have a uh esi cover for
the workers
right uh just on the uh this on the
copic 19
so the buyers on which are kind of you
know non-b2b to
see um are these kind of you know new
customers or
largely kind of existing customers kind
of you know topping up
for numbers so this typically would be
our own
existing sme customers or corporate
customers who have been dealing with us
who we have been in relationship for the
last few years
but the other part the benefit policy
that kovit 19 policy that we are selling
through
let's say digital platforms because this
is going to a segment which is probably
below our current customer base
yeah these are probably new customers
yes so b to b to c would be new
customers yes yes the b2b2 b2b
may be existing customers who have some
other relationship with us
okay thank you thank you
the next question is from the line of
motherboard from hdfc securities please
go ahead
hi good evening thank you for taking my
question uh
number one uh you know on the existing
benefit policies that we've written
would they
uh kind of get triggered with a kovit 19
case uh and what is our risk assessment
on that
uh so what sort of reinsurance do we
have
how well are we covered over there
thank you you want to touch upon that
and then i'll add to it if i want to
the current benefit benefit structure
the policies that we've
done in the past the covet claims
fundamentally don't get triggered on
that
there's clearly the instances are very
well listed and
at that point of time when we actually
had done the policy uh
there was nothing like a coronavirus or
covet which could have been
you know sought by the uh purchaser also
in future houses
involved we'll see it as it comes but as
of now
if someone wants a covert cover there's
a permit benefit policy as we spoke
about it
and a normal indemnity cover policy if
any customer has it they're fully
covered in terms of medical expenses on
that
so just to add to what sanji said our
benefit policies usually have
specific illnesses that are covered in
them these are critical business
policies
and these are reinsured with some of the
global uh leaders in reinsurance
okay but uh point to add to what we just
said in terms of your
question on risk i mean these are the
imponderables and you know
which we can't predict i mean if
suddenly there is some
uh regulatory pressure to pay for these
claims which are non-payable
those are things that we can't predict
as of now but they should not be because
these are not covered
right right uh and uh
how are uh motor renewals uh behaving so
far you know from
the last week of march until now
uh you would have a tp book you know od
book which would be renewing
uh what is customer behavior being up
there
there is a slight drop in retention
numbers
but we've seen for the month of march
because the last
few days we've seen a small drop in in
retention
uh but even in april we've seen a small
drop
uh i'll ask sanjiv to elaborate on it
but week on week we are seeing
improvement
sanjeev you want to add so clearly from
that perspective one regulator has given
dispensation and given continuity
benefits to the
policies which are following you between
the lockdown period
so some of them will be you know
to manage their own cash flows have
deferred their you know
renewers but that being said uh we have
seen
uh marginal drops uh if you go with
channel wise try to put across this
thing slightly more
you know sharper drop on the regular
side because the dancers are not active
and we are using various technology
based options like auto ninja
sending that quickly to get things
reviewed to remote calling or
robocalling
on the agency's side it's been even
better because agents are able to follow
up and then you know push these
customers into the
digital mode to you know do the but yes
as biology said there has been a
marginal drop
but a matter of time before it will come
in because there is a federal
requirement
also one more thing on the tp side which
i must mention that any new policy that
they sold
over last year were all long term so the
tp any which way is covered by enlarge
and
only the own damage part which needs to
be renewed
that's it from my side thank you thank
you
the next question is from the lioness
thank you from spark capital
please go ahead um yeah thanks for the
opportunity
uh this register wanted to understand
that moto tp launch features have now
fallen to
probably the best we have seen 78.5 in
the fourth quarter and the failure of
84. so just wanted to check whether this
is sustainable i believe this is largely
because of the increasing contribution
of two wheeler
then then if mixed changes due to any
reason uh
then do you think this is 84.5 kind of a
motorcycle operation sustainable or not
and we think with respect to third party
just wanted to understand uh
your view on the minimum quota formula
which has been changed based on the
non-insured vehicle
uh for motor tv business and whether to
what extent it will impact uh could be
an impact
on our overall tpd question number one
yeah sure so i think uh sanket uh i
think our approach to underwriting risk
is something that we have been talking
about for the last
so many quarters um yes the loss ratios
appear
is clearly a function of what kind of a
mix that we write in terms of private
car two-wheeler
and uh commercial vehicles one of the
things that you should be equally
mindful of is also the point that we
mentioned which is with respect to for
fi 21 so far
there is no rate hike that is being
proposed so
doing nothing that by itself will kind
of push up the
rtp loss ratios for the overall industry
and even for the portfolios that we
write
obviously it will have an impact in so
far as a loss ratio numbers are
concerned
having said that i think what we have
tried to do over the years
is to capture the opportunity of the
business mix
which we think are appropriate at
different points of time
and that in each of those occasions we
have recalibrated the mix
depending on the pricing environment
that operated and in that regard if you
would have seen what or
possibly the mix of business that we
write on the overall motor between
private car two-wheeler and commercial
vehicles i've undergone a significant
change even over the last
couple of years i mean you would have
seen those mixes when you would have
announced results let's say march 18
the mix of those three segments was very
different as compared to the mix of
business that we would you would have
seen for march 19
and even if you look at it for the
current year i think uh
the mix of business would be uh slightly
different so
in that sense obviously it's a function
of what kind of pricing environment
operates and within that we will
continue to
be this selective on the mix that we
would want to kind of
underwrite and keep looking for
opportunities so that we are able to try
and sustain
the overall profitability objective that
we have set for a comp
for ourselves as a company and that's
the way one would look at
how this loss ratios could play through
okay uh quota formula is yeah
changed with respect to tp or based on
the non-insured vehicle
we just wanted to understand whether it
will impact our business uh or or or
even basically sure so i think there
again i think if you look at the current
obligation i think purely is purely a
function of the value of the premium
that you write
and again there are been design defined
formulas basis which the quota is
determined and on that basis you are
expected to write a particular volume of
business
in order to meet your quota objectives
in so far as the new
norms are concerned i think the working
group has submitted their report
and rightfully so if you were to look at
in that context
i think the thought process of moving
the quota based
on the number of policies and then of
course there is also a factor of the
extent of the uninsured vehicles which
is also
that one has to consider is something in
that sense
uh acting in the right direction which
would ensure that
a larger section of the uh motor vehicle
owners
are taking an insurance policy uh
something that has been a challenge for
the industry as a whole so in that sense
when you look at the new
uh guidelines that has come through as a
part of the working group recommendation
it is definitely a step in the right
direction obviously we will have to
basis that recalibrate the mix of
business that we have to kind of write
between those private car two wheeler
and commercial vehicles
and ensure that we are in compliance
with the norms
but initial working do suggest that we
need to dramatically change our mix
in the sense that we comply with the
newer formula
it's all a function of as i said uh what
kind of uh
mix will that entail as i said you need
to kind of strike a right balance
between
all all the three segments whether it is
private car two wheel or commercial
vehicles
okay got it so is this this one broader
question when we said that maybe the
stronger companies will gain market
share
uh the post postcode
which segment you think the market share
gain could happen and whether you could
see
a again any price competition in in
those segments which
which you believe market share gain
could happen basically
uh you know this some of the segments
that we've seen this and
we've been talking about this shift in
any case without this uh
current uh event we've been saying that
gradually market share will shift to the
stronger companies
and some of the segments we've seen that
play through
so if you see even this year in certain
segments which
let's say for example fire segment where
pricing went up
last year our market shares increased
from
roughly about nine point three percent
to nine point eight percent uh
engineering market share increase so as
we said in the commercial lines
um definitely market share should uh
increase
in the sme segments given what we just
talked about
you know over this call in terms of
claim service also
the market share should increase we've
increased market share in motor own
damage we've now become the number one
company known damage
again because of some of these strengths
that we've built
and incrementally we are seeing faster
growth in the health segment
in the last maybe about two years um and
gopal gave the number for indemnity
growth
for this quarter uh you know
significantly higher than the market so
we
expect even their uh market share gains
to come through
uh i think that's the point is la you're
more generic i mean if you see
uh you know the overall uh mix if you
see the
private sector company earlier we used
to talk about uh
you know between the private and public
uh market share movement that you've
seen
but our senses if you see even in
private sectors
you know depending upon how where people
are and how the market plays out in
terms of claims etc
there are certain pressures that are
developing
we will see if that leads to some
relative benefit for us
definitely as i said because of balance
sheet technology capability and the fact
that
we've been able to manage this you know
engagement even in this period
we should see some benefit that's would
be our endeavor
okay this is the data keeping questions
can we give
the based on group health uh group
others which includes benefit based and
retail if it's possible
and vis-a-vis what happened in similar
number in the last year
so broadly frankie i think when you look
at the overall health portfolio i think
what we have also been talking about in
terms of
loss ratios behavior i think corporate
health will fundamentally as a business
line will have exhibit a high loss ratio
uh that number if you see has broadly
remained at about 93 94 percent
when whether you look at fi 19 or
whether you look at 520
and inherently again by the nature of
the business i think the retail
part of the business is something that
continues to exhibit a relatively lower
loss ratio experience and it does
tend to have a higher cost of
acquisition as we look at ramping up the
growth opportunity
again there if you have to look at the
uh indemnity loss ratios have also
kind of more or less remained at the
levels of sixty two six three percent
whether you look at uh fi 19 or whether
you look at uh f520
from group benefits
yeah yeah i know this uh contribution to
the people sorry
okay thank you the next question is from
the lineup akshay and tucker
from fl please go ahead hey
uh hi guys thank you for taking my
questions and uh thank you for doing
this call
uh i had actually the question on market
share which got addressed
by the previous scholars so i'll ask the
two follow-up questions one was on
duration on your fixed income book
could you just help us understand how
that's more through the
cocktail in that interest rates have
been volatile that was one
and second was through the year if
things remain tough
if uh inorganic opportunities come your
way
what are the areas within your industry
that you are open to
to look at just those two questions
thank you
um so on the second one uh we've always
said that we are
open to inorganic opportunities it
should
come at a price where we can deliver
value to our shareholders
in terms of giving a return and
if opportunities open up even at this
time we will always be open
we would look at what franchise
incrementally we get
out of it could be a certain
distribution franchise for certain
relationships
or certain businesses which could be
additive where we could something
see some synergy benefits otherwise so
the answer to that question is
yes open but it has to be at a price
that it makes sense for us
in terms of the duration of the
portfolio
if you see the overall duration of our
portfolio is about 3.72
at this point in time um the duration of
the portfolio
last year was about 4.76 we are keeping
it
uh keeping the duration a bit low
because uh
we've kept it low because we where uh
i mean from our perspective the long
duration bonds that did not give us an
adequate margin of safety
at the levels that it it was
of course one didn't anticipate a
pandemic so
to that extent it's gone down further
but uh pre pandemic at those rates we
were not
seeing the relative value we wanted to
keep our portfolio a
flexible so that we could reallocate our
bond
portfolio in a direction that we
preferred that was our
approach last year so we kept it
slightly low
so that we could swivel whenever we
wanted to
right now our uh our
uh you know approaches particularly you
know given the volatility that we've
seen
whenever we are seeing some market
dislocation and uh and interest rates
are going up
we are trying to lock in and slightly
increase the duration
okay thank you thank you
ladies and gentlemen due to the same
screen that was the last question
and now confidence
no thank you everyone thank you for
joining uh you know difficult times i
understand for
uh everyone and this is a saturday
evening uh though i don't know these
days where you can make out what is a
saturday or a friday
you for joining stay safe take care of
yourself
thanks thanks everyone thank you thank
you thank you
ladies and gentlemen on behalf of icici
lombard general insurance
that concludes this conference thank you
for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines